ABHISHEK MITTAL () Featured

5 Years 6 Month Experience as Software Developer in Microsoft Technologies(.Net(Dot Net), .NetCore, Angular,C#, MVC)



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Current Company: Accenture Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Gurgaon Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: Gurgaon, Noida, Delhi / NCR

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: ASP.Net,MVC,C#,SQL Server,Entity Framework,LINQ,ADO.Net,.NET Framework,Javascript,MVC

Architecture, Telerik Controls, WCF, Angularjs, angular 8, Angular 8, Angular 2, Angular 4, Angular

6, Mongo DB, Oracle, JQuery, HTML, NoSQL, CSS, UI Development, AWS, . NetCore

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 7-Jan-21

Summary

5 Years 7 Months experience as Software Developer in software design, analysis, development, testing and implementation of web and client server applications.

Hands on experience in application development using backend technologies like C#, Web Forms, MVC, Asp.Net, LINQ, Entity Framework, ADO.NET, Web API and web technologies like Angular 2/4/6/8, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, XML etc.

Having experience of databases SQL Server 2012, 2016 and Oracle 11G.

Experience with Code Repository tools like Tortoise SVN and Team Foundation Server.

Also Having exposure on Telerik Controls, BMC Remedy, Fortify Scan.

Work Experience

Accenture as Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2018 to Till Date

Working as a Software Developer to develop Web based applications using .Net, MVC Framework, AWS and Jquery,BootStrap,HTML,Angular 4 on front end side and also having direct interaction with client for requirement gathering and analysis.

Amdocs Development Centre India as Software Developer

Apr 2017 to Nov 2018

Working as a Software Developer to develop Web based applications using .Net, MVC Framework and Jquery,BootStrap,HTML,Angular JS on front end side and also having direct interaction with client for requirement gathering and analysis.

InterGlobe Technologies as Associate Software Engineer

Jun 2015 to Apr 2017

Software developer in asp.net,C#,MVC, ENTITY frame work Javascript, angular js, HTML ,CSS ,Jquery ,Ajax, Bootstrap, MySQL, SQL server 2014, Telerik Controls,Linq, Wcf, Web API, HP Fortify Scan, ADO.NET

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from Vidya college of engineering in 2015

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Microsoft 70-486 Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications

Microsoft 461: Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012/2014

Microsoft 483: Programming in C#

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C#		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Entity Framework		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Angular 8		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
BOOTSTRAP		2020	4 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
SQL Server		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
VISUAL STUDIO		2020	4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)
HP Fortify Scan		2020	4 Year(s) 3 Month(s)
Team Foundation Server		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Tortoise SVN		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Telerik Controls		2020	5 Year(s) 3 Month(s)
BMC Remedy		2020	5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
Sql SERVER Development		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Oracle		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Mongodb		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
HTML		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
CSS		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
JQUERY		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
JavaScript		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
LINQ		2018	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
ADO.NET		2020	5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
ASP.NET		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
MVC		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
ASP.Net MVC		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
MVC FRAMEWORK		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
MVC ARCHITECTURE		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Web API		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
WCF		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
WCF SERVICES		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
.net Framework		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
HINDI	Expert			
ENGLISH	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: My Industry Client: Accenture

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2018 - Till Date

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: My Industry is a portal i.e. using by Accentures clients to raise requests to install assets at their end. Assets

are nothing but the applications related to clients domain.

Project Title: CLEC SERVICE ORDER TRACKING SYSTEM

Client: AT&T

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Apr 2017 - Nov 2018
Project Location: Gurgaon Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 1

Skill Used: C#, Asp.net, Oracle 11g, Angular JS, Tortoise SVN, MVC

Role Description: Working as a software developer and also part of requirement gathering analysis and direct interaction with

client

Project Details: It is used to allow the CLECs to look out for their orders and the know their status

URL: https://orderstatus.wholesale.att.com/

Project Title: CIS GROUP NAVIGATOR

Client: CIS GROUP

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2016 - Apr 2017
Project Location: Gurgaon Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 5 Skill Used: C#,ASP.NET,TELERIK CONTROLS,JQUERY,SQL, MVC Framework

Role Description: I was working as a .net programmer with front end Technologies(Jquery,Bootstrap,HTML,CSS)

Project Details: It was a Property Insurance tool where the User can order a survey for their property after that Inspector Inspects the property and enter the property Information in our application based on that Our application calculate the

Insurance Amount and send it back to the User.

URL: https://navigator.cisgroup.net/Login.aspx

Project Title: EWAYS CARGO

Client: INDIGO

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2015 - Oct 2016

Project Location: Gurgaon Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: C#,Asp.net 4.5 ,jquery,javasciprt,html,css

Role Description: I was working as a .net programmer with front end Technologies(Jquery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS)

Project Details: It is a cargo management system of an airline and agent , it provides all the services from customer booking

request till the cargo will delivered and also we can track our cargo and many more.

Project Title: TOUR AND TRAVELS

Client: TRAVELPORT

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2015 - Oct 2016
Project Location: Gurgaon Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size

Skill Used: .Net,C#, ASP.Net MVC

Role Description: I was working as a .net programmer with front end Technologies(Jquery,Bootstrap,HTML,CSS)

Project Details: It provides all the necessary options related to Travel and Tourism to user like (Book Tickets of Trains and

Flights etc.).

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=043d6fab6687a75cfa00d4a2a5197c6059545f5919405b155512490e54...

Category: General Countries: Mexico

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time